MURPHY VAUGHN

Phone: 615.457.0185 | Email: vaughnmurphy89@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://proflonghair07.github.io/Murphy_Vaughn_Portfolio/
LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/murphy-vaughn-a256881a4
GitHub: https://github.com/proflonghair07

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer who specializes in front-end development. Makes applications with a clean and visually pleasing design. Has a strong work ethic derived from a long career in restaurant management. A strong ability to manage multiple responsibilities, work under stressful conditions, and streamline efficiency to meet time sensitive deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries: React.js, jQuery, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose

CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Bulma

Database Management Systems: MySQL, MongoDB

PROJECTS

Toddler Shopper — A mock shopping application for children Deployed Site - https://mighty-woodland-98663.herokuapp.com/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Toddler_Shopper_Twelve

- **Project Description** A mock shopping application for children that employs an interface that is similar to Amazon, but has a more kid friendly design, and prevents the user from seeing inappropriate material. This application is built as a MERN stack and has user authentication.
- **Contributions** Executed all of the frameworking in React.js. Styled the pages using the Bulma CSS framework. Applied all animations using Anime.js and Animate.css.
- **Technologies Used** MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, Bulma, Howler.js, React.js, Anime.js, Animate.css, and Node.js.

Trivia App — Randomly Generated Multiple Choice Trivia Quiz

Deployed Site - https://serene-inlet-83004.herokuapp.com/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Project_2

- Project Description A trivia application that pulls it's questions from the OpenTDB
 API. Allows the user to sign up via email and join or create a team. The Application
 stores the user's scores and averages team scores via a MySQL database.
- **Contributions** Responsible for all html templating and css styling. Developed the quiz portion of the app with vanilla Javascript and connected it to the OpenTDB api.
- **Technologies Used** Express.js, Handlebars.js, Node.js, Velocity, Bootstrap, MYSQL, Sequelize, and Node.js.

Employee Directory — An employee directory built with React.js

Deployed Site - https://proflonghair07.github.io/Employee Directory/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Employee_Directory

- Project Description An employee directory built with React.js. It allows the user to search for employees by their first name, sort employees by first name, and sort employees by age.
- Contributions Wrote all front-end Javascript and did all styling utilizing the Bootstrap CSS framework.
- **Technologies Used** React.js, Bootstrap, Axios, and Node.js.

Recipe App — Recipe App That Finds Recipes Based On User Input

Deployed Site - https://proflonghair07.github.io/Recipe_Finder/

Github Repository - https://github.com/proflonghair07/Recipe_Finder

- Project Description A recipe finding app that utilizes the Spoonacular api. Allows
 users to search for recipes by keywords, and filter the results to be either vegan,
 gluten-free, neither, or both.
- Contributions Created all HTML and CSS. Used the bulma framework for styling.
 Wrote all Javascript using jQuery.
- **Technologies Used** Bulma, Day.js, Spoonacular api, and jQuery.

EXPERIENCE

Executive Chef - Silo

May 2018 - March 2020

- Managed and staffed a Kitchen of 15 employees in a high stress environment.
- Wrote and maintained a seasonal menu.
- Established and maintained positive relations with a variety of vendors.
- Consistently maintained a food cost of 27% or lower.

Sous Chef - Cochon Butcher

July 2016 - Sep 2017

- Managed and staffed a Kitchen of 12 employees.
- Monitored food/labor costs, and recognized areas for improvement.
- Standardized recipes for consistent reproduction.
- Assisted executive chef in ordering and the inventory of products.

Sous Chef - Butchertown Hall

Feb 2015 – Sep 2015

- Trained and supervised new employees.
- Implemented systems to control product rotation.
- Supervised daily lunch operations while managing a prep team.
- Acted as head chef in the executive chef's absence.
- Developed and implemented procedures for operation in a new restaurant.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN — Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate

April 2020 - October 2020

Meridian High School, Meridian, MS — *Diploma*

Class of 2007